<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on NoProblemo</title>
    <link>https://abelgvidal.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on NoProblemo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This is my custom copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 20:03:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://abelgvidal.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reading notes: Ethics for Engineering</title>
      <link>https://abelgvidal.github.io/posts/eticaparaingenieros/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 20:03:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abelgvidal.github.io/posts/eticaparaingenieros/</guid>
      <description>This is a review of the book &amp;ldquo;Ética para ingenieros&amp;rdquo; by Galo Bilbao Alberdi, Francisco Javier Fuertes Pérez and José Mª Guibert Ucín.&#xA;The Engineering Profession Different sociological perspectives explore the meaning of professions, from traditional occupations like doctors or lawyers to modern professions requiring university education. The fundamental aspect of a profession is its unique service to society, a vocation that has intensified with modernity through &amp;ldquo;professionalization.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;There are notable concerns about the excesses of this process, such as the obsession with titles rather than service to society, distinguishing between &amp;ldquo;bad professionalism&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;good professionalism&amp;rdquo; oriented toward the community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Obsidian Talk with Google&#39;s Fancy Wavenet Voices</title>
      <link>https://abelgvidal.github.io/posts/obsidian-wavenet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 20:03:54 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://abelgvidal.github.io/posts/obsidian-wavenet/</guid>
      <description>Making Obsidian Talk with Google&amp;rsquo;s Fancy Wavenet Voices: A Quick Hack I&amp;rsquo;m sharing a little hack I put together. As a hardcore Obsidian user, I was getting frustrated with the available text-to-speech options. I really wanted to use Google&amp;rsquo;s Wavenet voices because they sound amazing, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a plugin that did exactly what I wanted. So I sorted it out myself.&#xA;I cobbled together a hack using Google Cloud&amp;rsquo;s Text-to-Speech API and Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s Shell Commands plugin.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
